Step aside.
靠边站
Hello? Hi.
喂 你好
The second elevator
二号电梯
has stopped on the 29th floor.
停在了二十九层
It might be a technical malfunction
应该是设备故障
or a power outage.
或者是断电了
Could you check it out?
您帮着查一下
[Okay, don't worry.]
好的不要着急
[Stay safe.]
注意安全啊
Okay.
好
Don't be scared.
不用怕
Will you marry me?
你愿意和我结婚吗
[Right,]
对了
have you decided today...
你今天考虑
I haven't decided yet.
我还没有考虑好
What I wanted to ask was that,
我是想问
have you decided what's for lunch today?
你今天考虑午餐吃什么
My treat.
我请你
I... I'm a bit busy today.
我 我今天有点忙
I don't have time for lunch.
没时间吃午饭
When I have some time,
等有时间的
I'll treat you.
我请你
Okay.
好
Let's get off.
赶紧下去吧
Tu Xiaoning,
涂筱柠
come to the meeting room with me.
跟我来趟会议室
She's only been here for a few days,
她才来几天
and now she has to leave.
这就要走了
What a pity!
真可惜啊
Did you help Zhou Kai do the
你帮周凯做的
commercial acceptance bill discounting.
商业承兑汇票贴现
Yes,
对
I did.
是我做的
[Discounting commercial acceptance bills]
商业承兑汇票贴现呢
[require bank endorsement]
需要银行背书的
along with undeposited paper tax invoices
未到期的纸质税票
and bills.
和汇票
[The bank has yet]
现在银行
[to receive the tax invoices]
迟迟收不到税票
because Zhou Kai has conspired with
因为周凯
invoice dealers and fled with the money.
勾结票贩携款潜逃了
You handled the filing
你替他归过档
as the secondary handler.
是第二经办人
You need to assist in the investigation.
你需要配合调查
Manager Rao,
饶经理
it was only a favour.
我只是帮他的忙
I swear I did not
我保证我绝对没有
collaborate with him.
跟他同流合污
Whether it was a favour or not
你帮不帮他忙
was none of my business.
跟我没关系
We are in a work place,
咱们现在在职场
not in a relationship.
也不是谈恋爱
[You don't need to swear your loyalty.]
你也不用跟我表忠心
Now many departments are looking for trouble
现在外面有很多部门
with the Business Development Department.
准备找拓展部的麻烦
And you
而你呢
have given them
给了他们一个
a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity.
千载难逢的好机会
So you mean,
意思是
I should take sole responsibility for it
让我自己负责
and resign to
然后辞职
save the Business Development Department?
保全拓展部吗
This does sound like
这个听起来呢
the most fitting option according
确实是最符合
to the principle of economic cost.
经济成本原则的
Okay,
好
I understand.
那我明白了
I can resign,
我可以走
but I can't leave
但我不能
while taking on such a big blame.
背这么大的一个黑锅走
I will prove my innocence.
我会自证清白的
I'll head out now.
我先出去了
[The punishment doesn't fit the crime.]
杀人不过头点地
Look
瞧瞧
how far you've forced the poor girl
给人家小姑娘
to go.
都逼到什么份上了
[When I had problems]
姐在职场上
[at work,]
遇见问题的时候
I never saw you being
我怎么没发现
this protective and caring.
你这么怜香惜玉啊
You're the iron lady of the banking world,
你是银行界的铁娘子
she's a delicate flower in a greenhouse.
她是温室里的小白花
[How can you compare that?]
那能一样吗
Are you really sure that
你就这么确信
she could do it?
她能做到啊
Of course I'm not sure!
我不确信啊
But I believe
但是我相信
one can do great when pushed to the edge.
置之死地而后生
[People who are too soft on themselves]
对自己太过慈悲的人呢
would not achieve breakthroughs.
是没有什么大突破的
What a breakthrough you've achieved!
你是突破得挺好的
If she can indeed pull this off,
如果这个事儿她做到了
then it will silence all external doubts
就能堵住所有外界
about the Business Development Department.
对于咱们拓展部的质疑
[If she can't,]
如果这个事她做不到呢
then the Business Development Department
咱们拓展部也不用
wouldn't be paying salary to
花薪资
someone useless anymore.
去养一个闲人
Killing two birds with one stone.
两全其美
You're truly egoist.
你是真利己啊
Then how about I go
那要不我去
tell President Jiang
跟江总说一句
that next month manager Zhao
咱们赵经理
won't need his salary anymore.
下个月的工资不要了
We will get paid with love.
我们用爱上班
President asked you to go to his office.
江总让你去他办公室
What does he need me for?
江总找我干吗
The documents on illegal discounting by
拓展一部
the Business Development Department
违规贴现的资料
are on your desk,
放你桌上
did you see them?
看到了吧
Yes, I did.
对 我看到了
The handler has run off,
经手人跑了
and apparently,
据说
the second handler
第二经办人
is a contractor, just a young girl.
是个劳务派遣的小姑娘
I feel that
我感觉
[contractors]
劳务派遣的能力
[are just not that capable.]
就是不行
[We need to investigate this thoroughly.]
可得好好查一查
When did the compliance department start
咱们合规部做事情
to do things based only on
什么时候靠的是
feelings and prejudices.
感觉和偏见了
[It's not okay.]
这可不行
Xiaoning,
筱柠
we're alone here.
这儿也没外人
You can tell me in secret, did
你悄悄告诉我
you really not collaborate with Zhou Kai?
你真的没跟周凯串通
I know
我知道
you probably won't believe anything
我说什么
that I say.
可能你们都不信
But I will find the proof,
但是我会找到证据的
to prove
证明
that I didn't work together with him.
我没有跟他同流合污
I told them that
我就跟他们说了
Xiaoning wasn't someone like that.
筱柠不是这种人
But they didn't believe me.
他们还不信
Speaking of Zhou Kai,
说起周凯
I remembered something else.
我还想起件事儿来
He still owes me 500 yuan,
他还欠我五百份子钱
still hasn't given it to me yet.
还没给我呢
[If you can get in touch with him,]
你要是联系到他了
[let me know.]
记得告诉我一声
Okay.
好
Don't be too stressed,
你也别太焦虑了
dear.
亲爱的
Still here after work?
下班了还不走
Let's go Xiaomang.
走了晓芒
Let's go.
走
I'll head out first then.
那我先走了
[There's no 'dear' in a work place.]
职场哪有什么亲爱的
[A nobody that can be tossed away]
我这样一个
[at any second like me,]
随时都能被丢弃的小卒
[can only save himself]
自救的方法
[by working hard.]
只有努力
[Xiaoning,]
筱柠啊
[you have been working in this bank]
你也在行里
[for a long time now,]
工作这么久了
[how can you not figure out]
怎么还看不清
[resources and connections are]
资源和人脉
[much more important than working hard.]
远远比勤奋更重要
[I just think that]
我就是觉得
[it should be fair.]
得公平
Fair?
公平
Fair exists only in court,
公平是法院给你的
not in a work place.
职场给不了你
Now there are many departments looking for trouble
现在外边有很多部门
with the Business Development Department.
准备找拓展部的麻烦
And you
而你呢
have given them
给了他们一个
a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity.
千载难逢的好机会
So you mean
意思是
I should take sole responsibility for it
让我自己负责
and resign to save
然后辞职
the Business Development Department?
保全拓展部吗
This does sound like
这个听起来呢
the most fitting option according
确实是最符合
to the principle of economic cost.
经济成本原则
[Hello,]
您好
[the number you've dialed is turned off.]
您拨打的电话已关机
[Sorry,]
对不起
Tu Xiaoning.
涂筱柠
Let's get married.
我们结婚吧
Nothing.
没什么
I once
我之前的时候
heard a saying that
听到了一个说法
rain
说下雨
is nature's fireworks,
是大自然的烟花
[and the sound of raindrops]
雨水滴答声
[is like the bursting of fireworks.]
是烟花的爆裂声
It was because of this saying
我以前就是因为这句话
that I used to like it when it rained.
才一直喜欢下雨的
And then,
后来
I realized that
我知道
the rain
原来下雨
would never turn into fireworks.
根本就不会变成烟花
Instead, it will splash mud everywhere.
反而会溅起一地的泥巴
Thanks for the coffee.
谢谢你的咖啡啊
It's very sweet.
很甜
I figured that you might
我想你这会儿
need something sweet in this moment.
可能需要一些甜的
So I added an extra piece of sugar
所以咖啡里面
in the coffee.
多加了一块糖
I almost forget,
我差点忘了
you work at the compliance department.
你是合规部的
Did you know about my things
我的事情
already?
你是不是早就知道了
Usually when old classmates meet up,
别人老同学见面啊
they either show off
不是炫耀自己
their successful careers,
事业有成呢
or
就是
their
展示自己
happy marriages.
婚姻幸福美满
I saw you a few times,
我跟你见了几面
and have already completely shown my
真是全方位无死角的
failed life
把我这失败的人生
from every possible perspective.
展示了一遍
No way.
不会啊
Unmarried at 27
二十七岁未婚
is not a failure.
不算失败
What about my job?
那工作呢
I worked in the lobby for three years.
我在大堂干了三年
If others are working hard,
如果说别人是努力工作
I was pushing myself to the limit.
那我就是拼命工作
But even so, I still
可是这么拼命
wasn't converted to a permanent employee.
我也没有转正
[Not only was I not converted permanent,]
没有转正不说吧
[I was also assigned to the Business]
我还被派遣到了
[Development Department, the so-called]
被说成是
Ningguta of the company. [*Ningguta was a remote, desolate area in ancient China.]
代瑞宁古塔的拓展一部
And the funniest thing is that
最搞笑的是
I won't even be able to stay
我现在连拓展一部
at the Business Development Department now.
我都待不下去了
My enthusiasm
我的热情
is truly no less than that of a
真的不比正式员工
permanent employee.
少一分
But mere enthusiasm is not enough.
那空有热情是不够的
If the problem is not solved,
问题解决不了
you still will be laid off.
你依旧还得卷铺盖走人
I know.
我知道
But I believe that
但我相信啊
anything that has been done
只要是做过的事情
will definitely leave a trace.
就一定会留有痕迹的
The reason I'm under suspicion now
我现在被怀疑
is because
是因为
those traces
那些痕迹
haven't been discovered yet.
还没有被人发现
But they must exist.
但是它一定存在的
I believe I will find them.
我相信我一定会找到的
So it's because of the meaning of
所以因为工作的
the work, and
意义
the effort you've put in these three years
因为这三年的付出
that you feel frustrated
你才会有挫败感
and malcontent,
和不甘
right?
对吗
Yes.
嗯
I knew it.
我就知道
This is the
这才是
Tu Xiaoning that I
我印象里边的那个
remembered,
涂筱柠
who never gives up easily.
不会轻言放弃的
Are you using
你在用
reverse psychology on me?
激将法吗
It's so cliché!
太老土了吧
But it does work,
但效果确实管用
doesn't it?
不是吗
Yeah.
嗯
Do you know how to solve the problem yet?
想好事情怎么解决了吗
You work at the compliance department,
你是合规部的哎
I am currently the subject of suspicion.
我现在是被怀疑的对象
Maybe we shouldn't be
好像我们两个
talking about this in private.
不能私底下聊这些吧
But I didn't
但是我可没跟你
reveal any
透露任何
compliance department's decisions to you.
关于合规部的处理办法
But work is work,
但工作归工作
and we still have
我们还是要
to follow the rules.
按规章办事的
Keep going,
加油吧
Tu Xiaoning.
涂筱柠同学
It's my duty,
职责所在
I won't be biased
处理你的问题的时候
when handling your problem.
我不会徇私的
Don't worry,
你放心吧
Ji Yuheng,
纪昱恒同学
I won't leave the Business Development
我不会那么轻易
Department so easily.
离开拓展一部的
Cheers!
干杯
[Please sit.]
坐吧
Let's start.
开始吧
Tu Xiaoning,
涂筱柠
[now we need to]
我们现在要针对
investigate and examine you
周凯的业务问题
regarding Zhou Kai's business issues.
对你进行了解和排查
As an employee at the bank,
作为银行的从业人员
you need to be accounted for
你需要对你接下来
the authenticity of every sentence
说的每一句话
and every word
和每一个字的真实性
that you are about to say.
来负责
[No concealment will be tolerated.]
不能有任何隐瞒
[Do you understand?]
听明白了吗
I understand.
明白
Let me ask you the first question.
我现在问你第一个问题
Did you assist in the two projects
周凯负责的这两个业务
that Zhou Kai was responsible for
你是否是
the entire process?
从头到尾协办的
No,
不是
I was only responsible for
我只负责
filing all the documents.
把所有的文件归档
[Preliminary data collection]
前期的收集资料
[and information input]
和信息填写
were all done by Zhou Kai
都是由周凯
himself.
亲自经手的
You can check this
这个可以在公司的
on the office URL.
办公网址上查到
Moreover,
而且
my chat history with Zhou Kai
我跟周凯的聊天记录
can also prove what I said.
也可以证明我所说的话
Here is
这是
my proof.
我的证据
Take a look at this.
你看看这个
Do you know what the exact performance
你有了解过一笔贴现
of a discounting transaction is?
具体的绩效是多少吗
No.
没有
Then why did you help Zhou Kai
没有你就帮着周凯
with these two transactions?
做这两个业务
Do you not care about
也不在乎自己
how your performance metrics is allocated
在这两笔业务里面的
in these two projects?
绩效分配吗
Although I'm a customer manager assistant,
我虽然是客户经理助理
but
但是
I'm a contractor,
我是劳务派遣工
[not a permanent]
不是银行
[bank employee.]
正式编制内的员工
[My salary calculation method]
我的工资计算法
[is different from that]
跟其他正式员工
[of other permanent staff.]
是不一样的
Without my own clients, naturally,
我没有自己的客户
I don't have any performance metrics.
自然就没有绩效
The evidence I provided includes
我提供的证据里面
[the transaction records of my salary]
有我的工资卡流水
[card and all bank cards]
以及我名下
[under my name.]
所有银行卡的流水
[They can prove that]
它们可以证明
[I have never received]
我从来都没有收到过
[any]
任何一笔
performance bonuses
绩效款项
or any funds
以及任何一笔
from unclear sources.
来路不明的款项
Do the things you mentioned above
以上你说的这些
involve any concealment?
有没有隐瞒
No.
没有
We knew more or less about the situation.
情况我们大致都了解了
You can go back now.
你可以先回去了
Thanks.
谢谢
I have another question.
我还有一个问题
The companies
这两笔业务
didn't provide
当时的企业
any tax invoices at the time,
是没有提供税票的
did you know that?
你可知情
Yes.
知道
According to our back's regulations on
我行对贴现的规定
discounting, if a company can't provide
如果企业无法当场
the tax invoices at the moment,
提供税票
and if in an urgent business situation,
并且业务紧急的情况下
they can provide it later within a month.
可以在一个月内补齐
Zhou Kai is nowhere to be found now.
周凯现在不知所踪
You were the one that did the filing,
当时是你归的档
so you were the second handler.
你就是第二经办人
The bank is
行里对这个事情
highly concerned about this.
高度关注
[Can you provide any]
你还能提供
other evidence?
其他的线索吗
[Don't panic,]
别慌
[there must be other traces.]
一定会有其他痕迹
[Zhou Kai,]
周哥
[you don't have the tax invoices]
您这两份文件
[for these two documents.]
没有税票
[I know.]
我知道
[I'll ask them to provide it these days.]
这两天我就让他们补齐
[Okay, Zhou Kai.]
好嘞周哥
[But,]
不过
[you need to sign]
您得先给我补签一下
[this commitment letter for me first.]
这个承诺书
[Sure, I'll do it tomorrow.]
行 明天再说
[I'm afraid that can be.]
那恐怕不行
[I can't do the filing if ]
文件不全
[there are documents missing.]
我不能帮您归档
[This is the rule of the bank.]
这是行里的规矩
[If you can not come back,]
您要是不方便回来
[I can bring it to you.]
我给您送过去
I do have the proof.
我有证明
Though the tax invoices are not complete,
虽然税票没有补齐
the customer manager
但需管户客户经理
must provide a tax invoice commitment,
提供税票承诺
[and]
并且
[have it signed]
由其余
[by the heads of other departments.]
部门负责人签字
This tax invoice commitment
这份税票承诺
should now be
现在应该在
in the archive room.
档案室里
Director,
主任
I have no further questions.
我没有其他问题了
You can go back now.
你先回去吧
[Brovo!]
好
Jing,
静姐
I said I would prove my innocence.
我说过我会自证清白的
Good, you didn't implicate
很好
the Business Development Department.
没有连累拓展一部
Don't worry about her.
别理她
[Look at]
瞧瞧
[what this is.]
这是什么
Isn't this
这个
from my
不是我
shopping cart?
购物车里的东西吗
As long as my friend likes it,
只要是我姐妹喜欢的
even if it's a pearl in the sky,
哪怕是天上的遗珠
I will still find a way to get it.
我也给它摘下来
This wasn't easy to buy.
还挺难买的
Thank you.
谢了
Sure.
好吧
As long as you're happy.
你开心就好
Is it spicy?
辣不辣
It's good.
好吃
Maybe we should get married.
要不咱俩结婚得了
If we got married,
咱俩结婚
it would definitely last forever.
绝对百年好合
And we would be happier than
幸福指数能超过全世界
90% of the married couples in the world.
百分之九十以上的夫妻
Sure,
行啊
quit your job first.
先把你那班辞了
Don't be too stubborn to stay at Dairui.
也别跟什么代瑞死磕了
For others, work is just work,
我看别人上班是上班
but for you,
你上班像取经
it's like a series of ongoing challenges.
步步劫难
This time
这次吧
was indeed
确实
a bit dangerous.
有点惊险
But fortunately
还好
I had some help.
有贵人相助
From whom?
谁
Your
你那个
ex classmate slash colleague?
稻草同学兼同事
Yes.
嗯
He gave me a heads-up before
他事先提点了我
to pay attention
让我注意
to the details underneath the rules.
规则以下的细节
[And during the inquiry,]
而且在问询的时候
[he appeared to be very strict,]
他表面上很苛刻
but in reality,
实际上
he asked a lot of about the
问了很多
details that everyone else overlooked.
大家都忽略的地方
It not only cleared me of suspicion
不但让我洗脱了嫌疑
but also showed people at Dairui
还让代瑞的人看到了
my professionalism.
我很专业的一面
He is outstanding,
条件优秀
meticulous and precise.
严谨细心
I think he's interested in you.
我觉得他对你有意思
He proposed to me.
他跟我求婚了
What?
什么
Proposed?
求婚
Yeah.
嗯
Did you say yes?
你答应了
Of course not.
当然没有
I've only seen him a few times,
我才见几面啊
how can I marry him?
我就跟他结婚
So what?
这有什么呀
Why would someone as good as him
人家条件那么好
choose me?
凭什么选我
It doesn't matter why he chooses you,
你管他为什么选你
as long as you're clear on
你想清楚
why you choose him,
你为什么要选他
that's enough.
不就好了吗
Someone like Ji Yuheng,
像纪昱恒这种条件
if you let him go,
你要是一撒手
he'll be snatched up in the
把他放回相亲市场
blind dating market.
准没了
Can't find another like him!
找不出第二个
That's true.
那倒也是
With his qualities,
他这条件
he's definitely
绝对属于
a catch.
入股 不亏的那种
And even though
而且我虽然
we don't hang out often,
跟他接触少吧
every time I'm with him,
但每次跟他相处
I feel at ease.
我都觉得挺心安的
You know each other inside out,
因为你俩知根知底
and fate even brought
而且还在人生的这个
you together
相亲阶段
in a blind dating.
偶遇了
[Plus, he's asking you]
他还对你发出了
[to marry him.]
结婚的邀请
You are born
你们这不是
to be a couple.
月老拧钢筋的缘分吗
Why not rush things a bit?
不是流程快点怎么了
Think about Lu Sijing,
你想想看陆思靖
he ended up
到头来呢
with neither
稳定的婚姻没有
a solid relationship
激动的爱情也没有
nor exciting love.
啥啥没有
Yeah, that's true.
那倒也是
He
陆思靖呢
taught me a lesson.
是给我上了一课
Now I know that
他让我知道
time doesn't
时间的长短
always equal
没有办法决定
a good marriage.
结局的好坏
So, a flash marriage
所以要这么说的话
could
闪婚
still work out,
未必没有好的结局
right?
是吧
Yeah.
对啊
From what you say,
而且我从你的
he sounds
字里行间不难看出
way better than
虽然我没有见过这个人
Lu Sijing,
但是
even though
他绝对可以
I haven't met him.
把陆思靖秒成渣
Lu Sijing used to
我还记得这个 陆思靖
trash your job
当时说你是什么
just because
劳务派遣
it was temp work.
看轻你的工作
[What the hell?]
想到我就来气
But now you've got a great guy.
如今你寻得了良人
Let him eat his heart out.
扎他一记回旋镖
Don't sweat the small stuff.
这有什么好生气的
What?
你干吗
Show off
让我跟他演出戏
in front of him?
小人得志
Of course not.
什么小人得志
It's ambition and pride.
我们这叫有志气
Okay.
行
Got it.
我知道了
Let me think about it.
我好好想想
Here.
赵经理
Thanks.
谢谢
Xiaoning.
小涂
Compliance Dept. didn't
周凯这件事
hassle you much about Zhou Kai.
合规部对你没太为难
Any connections there?
是不是有什么熟人啊
If I do, why am I
我要是有熟人的话
still temp
三年都不转正
after 3 years?
不太现实吧
Come on.
别不好意思吗
Use your
这关系啊
connections.
你不用它
It can help you a lot.
它就是死的
They're worthless
你用它
if left unused.
就全活了
No, really.
真没有
That's not how it is.
赵经理你误会了
Fine.
行
Drop it then.
那咱们不谈这个
Let's talk about your job.
说说你转正的事儿吧
Work for me.
来哥这儿
I'll make you permanent.
转正一句话的事儿
[Fanggang.]
赵经理
I heard you make great coffee.
听说你泡咖啡很有一手
Mind making me one?
那麻烦帮我泡一杯呗
I've got this fresh cup, want a sip?
我这杯没喝过你喝吗
I don't wanna use your cup.
你的杯子就算了
We're peers.
咱俩都是同级
Making you coffee
让我帮你泡咖啡
is not my job, huh?
不合规矩吧
Since you're
赵经理是一个
so rule-conscious,
讲规矩的人
[you should know that]
那赵经理知不知道
Tu Xiaoning
涂筱柠
is working for me.
现在是在我的手下
She's my assistant.
我的助理
[If you want her]
以后让我助理
[to brew you coffee,]
给你泡咖啡这种事情呢
give me a heads-up.
您最好通知我一下
Let's play by the rules.
以免坏了规矩
Xiaoning.
小涂
One of my clients
我之前有一个客户
got hurt
受伤了
and is at Renji Hospital.
在仁济医院住院部
I'm busy with Mr. Jiang,
我这边跟江总有点事
I'll meet you there.
忙完过去跟你汇合
On my way.
好 我马上去
[I'm off.]
走了姐
Be careful.
路上注意安全啊
Rao Jing.
饶静
Are you picking a fight?
存心跟我杠上了是吧
When the new girl's here,
新人面前
just do me a favor.
能给我点面子吗你
[Hello? Jing.]
喂 静姐
Just saw Mr. Li.
我刚才看到李老先生了
His left hand injury
他伤的是左手
is healing up nice.
看样子恢复得还不错
Don't think he'd mind a visit.
应该不会拒绝见客
Okay, got it.
行我知道了
I'll be there.
我忙完就过去啊
I just spoke with
我刚才私下
his carer in private.
接触了一下他的护工
Some bank guy
好像今天早上
was here earlier today.
有别的银行的人也来过
Got it.
我知道了
On my way.
现在就过去
Hello?
喂 你好
A bunch of sunflowers.
我要订一束向日葵
Delivered to Renji Hospital.
送到医院
Okay.
好
Thanks.
谢谢啊
Ji Yuheng?
纪昱恒
Why is he here?
他怎么在这儿
[Who is it?]
谁呀
Sorry.
不好意思阿姨
Wrong place,
我走错了
my bad.
打扰了
Tu Xiaoning?
涂筱柠
Why are you here?
你怎么在这儿呢
[Xiaoning?]
筱柠
You're Xiaoning?
你就是筱柠
[Yuheng's girlfriend?]
昱恒的女朋友
[Come in.]
来 来 来
Mom.
妈
Doc said you should lie down.
医生说您不能老坐着
[Why're you up?]
怎么就起来了
[Been lying down all day...]
我这天天躺着
I...
这
Xiaoning's here.
筱柠来看我了
I'm so happy.
我开心啊
Come here.
快来 快来
Nice to meet you.
阿姨
Sorry for the delay,
不好意思啊
finally got to see you.
今天才来看您
It's fine.
这个 没事
These are for you.
这个给您
That's very kind of you.
你还买这么多东西
It's okay.
没事的 没事的
Yuheng always says
昱恒一直说
you're very busy with work.
说你工作很忙
Careers
年轻人
come first for you young ones.
要以事业为重的
Come.
来 来 来
Xiaoning.
筱柠
Sorry for all the mess.
你看我
Our first
第一次见你
meeting, huh?
我就这个样子
Please don't mind.
失礼了啊
Nah...
不会阿姨
You're still shining bright.
你现在一样光彩照人
[Listen to the doc and]
好好听医生的话
[get well soon.]
养好身体
She's so nice.
这孩子真会说话
Xiaoning.
筱柠
Yuheng's
昱恒呢
always been
打小
a quiet type.
就沉闷
He keeps
他是那种啊
his thoughts
好多话放在心里
to himself.
不说出口的人
[Bear with him, will you?]
你要多担待
He's
他
good.
挺好的
But
但是
he's the type
他要是开了口
to stick to
那就是承诺
his words.
会认真一辈子的
Looking at
一看到你们俩
you two,
都在我面前
[I can't help]
我这心里
but wonder
就忍不住要想
what
你们
your
结婚
married life will be like
会是什么样子啊
and how
小孩子
adorable your baby will be.
肯定也会特别可爱
Mom!
妈
Ma'am!
阿姨
Lie down.
咱先躺着
Are you okay?
阿姨你没事吧
Alright.
来
Hey.
咱们家属先出去来
Please.
不好意思
Excuse me.
家属先出去
Please
辛苦了
save her.
麻烦大夫
Excuse me.
不好意思
Clear the way.
家属先出去
Step outside.
家属往外走啊
Excuse me.
不好意思
Doc.
医生
How's my mom?
我妈情况怎么样了
Rescue's over,
她刚躺下
give it a minute before you go in.
你过会儿再进去吧
She's not
她现在情况
doing well.
不太好
It's gonna cost a lot
你妈妈现在这种情况啊
[for]
后续治疗
[her treatment.]
需要大量的费用
and we can't
而且即便是这样
say for sure
我们也不敢保证
how long she's got.
她还有多少时间
Be ready for the worst.
你要做好心理准备
[Any chance to save her,]
只要还能有一点希望
[I'm in it to the end.]
我不会放弃的
Thank you.
辛苦您了
Breast cancer,
乳腺癌
late stage.
晚期
Mom's
我妈她
been through chemo.
一直在做化疗
Don't worry 'bout me.
其实不用说什么
We're all
大家都是普通人
in the same boat,
都会遇到
facing our struggles.
这样那样的难题
Thanks for not revealing
刚刚还是要感谢你
the truth to my mom.
没有拆穿我
She's just
我妈她
afraid I'll be lonely,
就是怕我一个人太孤单
so she...
所以她
Got a clue
我大概知道
why you're so
你为什么
marriage-minded.
这么着急结婚了
I get it.
理解
But she seems
不过我感觉
to know me.
阿姨好像认识我
You talked about me with her?
你跟她提起过
She's
我妈她
just anxious
会担心我现在
I'm still single.
怎么还没找女朋友
We had a
前段时间
class reunion, remember?
咱不是同学会吗
I told her I caught up
我跟她提到
with an old school friend,
见到了一个老同学
but she got the wrong idea.
所以她误会了
Hello?
喂 你好
Hold on,
你在那儿等我一下
I'm coming.
我马上过来
Thanks.
谢谢
You've got things to do, huh?
来医院还有事情吧
Go ahead.
先去忙吧
If you need anything,
那你要有什么需要
just call me.
给我打电话
Thanks.
谢谢
Mom.
妈
You're awake.
醒了
First time Xiaoning saw me,
筱柠 第一次见我
and I was all sickly.
我就这样
Must've scared her.
吓坏她了吧
Nah.
没有
Her work called,
她单位有事情
she had to bail early.
先提前回去了
When you're still at school,
念书的时候
you often talked about her.
就总听你提起她
Now that she's your girlfriend,
现在成了女朋友了
I finally got to meet her.
我也总算见到了
But I didn't even
可惜我都没给她
have a proper gift for her.
准备个像样的礼物
Never mind.
没有
Mom.
妈
Xiaoning's cool about it.
筱柠 她没在意
I told her
而且我跟她说了
you'd pick out
等过两天
a gift for her soon.
您会再亲自
She was very happy
挑选一个礼物给她
after hearing that.
她听了可开心了
Really?
真的
Yeah.
当然
So,
所以说
you gotta get well soon.
您赶快养好身体
Then we can pick out
咱们一起
the best gift
挑一个最好的礼物
for her.
送给她
Yeah, gotta pick the best...
那真的是要好好想想
Xiaoning.
筱柠
You're still here?
怎么还没走
Night market...
小吃街
It's also called "Human Train",
也叫人形回转寿司
where the food stays put,
就是这些好吃的不动
we shuffle around.
我们动
You're not used to
你不会不习惯
this kinda place, are you?
这种地方吧
Indulging in
上学的时候
snacks on a food street
如果能在小吃街
without worrying about money?
实现美食自由的话
That's every
那是每个
broke uni kid's fantasy.
穷大学生的梦想
I'm totally fine with this place.
我当然不会不习惯
You sure?
我不信
Let's see.
要不试试
Hi.
老板
Two servings of stinky tofu.
帮我拿两份臭豆腐
Coming up.
好的
Just alright.
这味道也一般呀
Needs more frying time
炸的时间不够久
for that crunchy skin.
外皮儿不够酥脆
And
另外
the sauce's way too
汤汁太少
watery and bland.
不够浓
Our school's stinky tofu's the best.
不如我们学校的好
Ours' the best.
我们学校才不服气呢
Let's go.
走
The next.
下一项
I couldn't eat another mouthful.
我已经到这儿了
I'm stuffed!
撑死我了
I'll grab you some
一会儿我给你买点
indigestion meds.
健胃消食片
Nah.
不用
Medicine
化学治疗
can't beat a good walk.
不如物理治疗
Come with me.
跟我走
Why'd you wanna come here?
怎么突然想到来这儿了
Just walking around,
我就是想走走
thinking about
回味一下
the good old college days
不用为生活发愁
when life was simple,
不用为工作担忧
we were stress-free
没有失败感情的
and had no
大学生活
failed relationships.
多好呀
I was eagerly looking forward
那个时候我也期盼着
to graduation,
能够快点毕业
thinking I could
因为很多事情
only do grown-up stuff then.
只有大人才能去做
Me too. I was
我也有期盼着
hoping for an
我期盼着有一份
inspiring job,
向阳而生的工作
a happy marriage,
一场幸福可见的婚姻
and
和一个
a bright future.
可以憧憬的未来
Sounds good.
听起来很不错
Got a plan to make it happen?
想好怎么实现了吗
I'll give it my all
虽然拓展部
in the Business
不是我自己想要来的
Development Department,
但是我既然来了
even though it's not
我一定会全力以赴
my first choice.
好好工作的
As for marriage,
至于婚姻
I have seriously
你的提议
considered your proposal.
我有认真地考虑过
Spending some time with you,
接触了几次
I think you're
我觉得你是一个
a great choice
很好的人
for
很适合
marriage.
步入婚姻的人
But
只是
I always have a question.
我一直有一个疑问
Why me?
为什么是我
Even if you're in a hurry,
即便是为了阿姨
you're good
你的条件
and you could have anyone.
也会有很多个选择
Why me?
为什么选择我
Because you make me
因为跟你在一起
feel right and
我有一种契合感
safe.
和安心感
Yeah.
确实
We're
我们两个
on the same page a lot.
很多地方都很同频
Maybe because we're classmates
那我可不可以理解为
and know each other
因为我们是同学
inside out.
知根知底
Love is not
婚姻中
the only thing in marriage.
不一定非要有爱情
Comfort and stability count too.
舒适稳定也很重要
You're right.
你说得对
Keep your
用不期待的态度
expectations low
去铺垫婚姻的底色
for marriage, and you'll
说不定之后的每一天
find joy in every day.
都能有惊喜
Low expectations,
只要起点够低
easy happiness.
幸福感就够高
But my job's
不过我现在
a hot mess,
工作一塌糊涂
feels unfair to drag you into this.
对你有点不太公平啊
Nah.
怎么会
Career's just a slice,
事业只是生活的一部分
marriage's
婚姻的意义
got more to it.
也不应该只有这一层
Look.
你想
If we do
如果真的
tie the knot,
步入了婚姻殿堂
imagine coming home
累了以后有一个人
to find someone waiting,
在家里等着你
watching a movie together,
两个人一起看场电影
brainstorming work woes,
遇到棘手的工作了
and venting about
可以互相商量一下对策
work and
一起吐槽工作
bosses.
和领导
Isn't that sweet?
这不都是婚姻的好处吗
That
听上去
sounds good.
还挺不错的
No rule says
没有任何人
you gotta
有过规定
be rich
是不是
and famous
只有功成名就了之后
to get hitched.
才能够结婚
My dream marriage
我理想当中的婚姻
is one where
应该是两个人一起
we have
期待一下
high expectations for
未来的生活是什么样
our future life
打开看看
and truly experience it.
那里面到底是什么
Right.
是
Take the leap,
只要勇敢地
who knows,
开始一个新的生活
the answers
说不定
might be waiting.
就有正确答案了呢
Ji Yuheng.
纪昱恒
I've made up my mind.
我想好了
Let's get married.
我们结婚吧
[Tomorrow.]
明天就去领证
Cool!
嗯
Yuheng.
小恒
Your dad's gone.
你爸爸不在了
Just
以后这个家
us two now.
就剩我们两个人了
Word on the street
外面都在传
is your dad taking bribes,
你爸爸受贿
and he died just like that.
偏巧他这个时候去世了
Could've been
谁知道是不是
a guilty conscience.
畏罪自杀呀
With his dad's scandal,
他爸出了那样的事情
no one's near him.
谁还敢跟他打交道啊
Hunk or not,
校草学霸又能怎么样
dad's a crook.
他爸爸不还是罪犯吗
Rousong.
肉松
Hey.
喂
Don't jump!
你别冲动
You okay?
没事吧
The kitten's okay.
应该没伤到
I mean,
我是问你
are you okay?
你没事吧
Ji Yuheng, right?
纪昱恒 是吧
I've heard
我其实听到过
stuff about you,
你的一些事情
not much detail,
就是偶尔听别人说起
[not sure if it's true.]
确实也不是很清楚
But I wanna tell you,
但是我就是想跟你说
focus on the future.
凡事你得往前看
Looking back
你一直往后看
only brings losses.
就经常要面对失去
Keep moving forward,
但是往前看的话
you'll find
就会有很多
new things.
不一样的收获
Don't forget
下雨天
your umbrella on rainy days,
要记得打伞
or you'll catch a cold.
要不然会感冒的
Take care.
照顾好自己
Here, take mine.
我这把伞给你吧
It'll help you get through this,
帮你撑过最难的时候
and the sun will shine again.
等雨过天晴
Take it.
拿着呀
Let's go.
走了肉松
Bye.
走了